# Kirsty Baker, Curriculum Vitae

#### **Profile**

Kirsty is an empowering leader, a though-provoking catalyst for change and a unique creator of strategic partnerships. Through her experience in all three sectors, Kirsty has demonstrated consistently that she is a thinker and a strategist, grounded in solid analysis and evidence, and focussed on organisational improvement and individual growth and development. As shown in her most recent role, Kirsty is an influencer and negotiator, the voice of reason and a strong communicator. She provides an independent view and an outside perspective grounded in knowledge and experience. Kirsty is an engaging, competent and confident professional, able to build successful relationships and quickly engender trust in people of all levels and from all backgrounds and to deliver on commitments in challenging and sensitive situations. She created The Firefly Group, a leadership development company, partnering with leaders and leadership teams to help them deepen their impact and strengthen their effectiveness.

# **Professional Experience**

The Firefly Group

May 2011 - present

Founder & Director

Provider of leadership development solutions for organisations, teams and individuals, focussed on deepening leadership impact and enabling organisational change. Clients include BSkyB, JP Morgan, Scottish Ambulance Service, Education Scotland, The Scottish Government, Edinburgh University and not-for-profit collaborations with Scottish Business in the Community, and ACOSVO (Association for Chief Officers of Scottish Voluntary Organisations).

Scottish Government

November 2011 - present (to complete May 2013)

Interim Manager

Programme lead for organisation-wide transformational change programme designed to reduce the size of the workforce by 20% over a three year period, whilst implementing the changes to ensure the organisation not only continues to deliver but does so in a way that allows for potential future constitutional reform.

Scottish Government

March 2009 - November 2011

Interim Manager

Head of defence strategy and resilience strategy in Scotland, challenging policy area on the boundaries of devolution, directly answerable to the First Minister and the Permanent Secretary.

Accenture Consulting

December 2000 - January 2009

Consulting Executive

Head of Corporate Citizenship for Scotland (P/T)

Financial services consulting manager with specialisms in regulatory change and programme management in banking.

Clients included: Abbey, Bank of Ireland, Barclays, LloydsTSB, Morgan Stanley, OCBC Bank (Singapore), Prince's Scottish Youth Business Trust, Prince's Youth Business International, Sainsbury's, Scottish Financial Enterprise and United Overseas Bank (Malaysia).

Royal Bank of Scotland

October 1998 - December 2000

**Business Analyst** 

Business analyst focussing on organisational change and joint venture management.

### **Academic Credentials**

Certified Professional Co-Active Coach (CPCC) 2012

Chartered Banker (MCIBS) 2007

Msc Organisational Behaviour 2004

Birkbeck College, University of London

BA (Hons) Combined Arts 1998

University of Durham

## **Professional Interests**

Kirsty has particular professional interests in strategy, organisational change and development, employee engagement and leadership.